Daniel Pinedo

□+1 213-999-5619 | **■** daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu | **♠** pinedo.org

Introduction_

I have extensive experience as a statistician, data scientist, evaluation scientist, university lecturer, and organizational psychologist.

My background and experience has varied over the years from IT network administration and management to most recently Global HR consulting and analytics and data science support for program evaluation. I delight equally in employee relations, learning and development, crunching numbers, and consulting with and advising global leaders.

I am highly proficient in presenting and lecturing; and using the reporting tools Excel, Tableau, Power BI, R, and Python.

Education ___

Claremont Graduate University

Claremont, CA

MA PSYCHOLOGY

Sep 2018 - May 2020

• Concentrations in Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

Sofia University

Palo Alto, CA

MA Psychology

Sep 2010 - May 2013

Concentration in Clinical Psychology

Naropa University

Boulder, CO

BA TRADITIONAL EASTERN ARTS

Sep 2008 - May 2010

• Student Government: Treasurer

Professional Experience _____

Sep 2019 - present	Principal , Kinesis Consulting (20 hours / week)
--------------------	---

Nov 2018 - Jun 2020 Consultant, Accenture Plc, CGU Talent Innovation Lab (20 hours / week)

Sep 2016 - May 2018 Lecturer, Psychology, Mount Saint Mary's University (full time)

Aug 2014 - July 2015 Clinician, Sovereign Health Group, adult partial inpatient rehabilitation center (full time)

Aug 2013 - July 2014 Clinician, Mind Body Awareness Project, adolescent drug and alcohol counseling (20 hours / week)

Aug 2012 - July 2013 Clinician, San Mateo County juvenile detention center, forensic psychological evaluation (20 hours / week)

Aug 2011 - July 2012 Clinician, Lifemoves family homeless shelter, individual & family therapy (20 hours / week)

2002 - 2008 IT Consultant, network engineering specialist (full time)

Evaluation_

Kinesis ConsultingPhoenixville, PAROLE: PRINCIPALSep 2019 - present

• Statistical consultation including social science methodology, visualization, and presentation in support of policy & planning analysis and program evaluation for the scientific community. Focus is on methodological innovation for evaluation in support of climate change mitigation and resilience infrastructure projects. Examples of recent projects:

- Survey analysis and presentation for external program evaluation in NSF Directorate for Geosciences
- Mixed method / Social network analysis for external program evaluation in NSF Division of Undergraduate Education
- Social network analyses for external program evaluation in NSF Office of Integrative Activities.

Consulting _____

Accenture Talent Innovation Lab

Claremont, CA

Nov 2018 - Jun 2020

ROLES: CONSULTANT, PROJECT MANAGER, TEAM LEAD

- Global HR / Recruitment Transformation Research & Development Lab
- Managed project deliverable content and translated research into business cases.
- Consulted with stakeholder managers on organizational behavior, management, statistics, research methods, interviewing, and focus groups.
- · Led project teams.
- Managed performance and career development.
- Managed project timelines, milestones, personnel time, and budgeting.
- Trained team on client on-boarding, acculturation, pitching and public speaking, time management, technical mentoring, and cross-functional communication.
- Created interviewing/hiring criteria as member of Recruitment and Selection Committee.
- Served as resource for strategy insights and revenue ideas.
- High-impact project examples include:
 - Future workplace job redesign research and market analysis for account executive role
 - Documentation sprint to prepare final presentation of vetted global employee selection and assessment model
 - Validation of scoring measure for behavioral interview
 - Development of values-based assessment prototype
 - Selection assessment design prototype
 - Leadership model synthesis and design

Claremont Graduate University

Claremont, CA

Sep 2018 - May 2020

DEPT OF BEHAVIORAL AND ORGANIZATIONAL SCIENCES

- Evaluation plan for North America regional HR client organization Arup
- Intensive organizational behavior assessment center for Getty Leadership Center
- · Organizational culture project for private, family-owned property management firm
- Organizational behavior project for ICM Partners creative talent agency undergoing HR restructuring
- · Competition: BCG Datathon team leader for invitation only data science business case competition

Publications __

PUBLISHED

Himelstein, S., Saul, S., Garcia-Romeu, A., & **Pinedo, D.** (2014). Mindfulness training as an intervention for substance user incarcerated adolescents: A pilot grounded theory study. *Substance Use & Misuse*.

Kaczmarczyk, L., & **Pinedo, D.** (in press). Getting things done in data intensive inter-campus research initiatives: A social network analysis approach to understanding and building effective relationships between researchers and other university employees. In *Proceedings of the 2021 American Society for Engineering Education Annual Conference & Exposition* (Vol. 26)

Presentations _

INVITED TALKS

Spring 2018, Fall 2017. ⁺ Coordination of symposium and opening speech on topic of importance of promoting undergraduate research and representation of women in STEM. Invited talk: Undergraduate research symposium, Mount Saint Mary's University, Los Angeles, CA

CONTRIBUTED PRESENTATIONS

Himelstein, S., & **Pinedo, D.** (2013). Empowering communities: An intensive mindfulness training in a retreat setting for college-bound adolescents and college-aged tutors. [Meditation Retreat]. Redwood Glen Summer Camp; Loma Mar, CA.

Himelstein, S., **Pinedo, D.**, & Mousseau, A. (2013). *Mindfulness training for educators: An intensive training at the Lakota Nation at Pine Ridge.* [Inservice Training]. Little Wound High School; Kyle, SD.

Kaczmarczyk, L., & **Pinedo, D.** (July 2021). Getting things done in data intensive inter-campus research initiatives: A social network analysis approach to understanding and building effective relationships between researchers and other university employees. [Poster Presentation]. The 2021 American Society for Engineering Education Annual Conference & Exposition. Long Beach, CA.

^{*} mentored undergraduates

Pinedo, D., Gutierrez, G., & Tinoco, C. (2013). Assessment, prevention, and discussion of health disparities in local Native American populations [Continuing Education Training]. Health Services Building, San Mateo, CA.

Awards, F	Fellowships, & Grants	
2018	Graduate Fellowship, Claremont Graduate University	\$ 20,000
2008	President's Scholarship, Naropa University	\$ 10,000
Outreach	& Professional Development	
SERVICE AN	D OUTREACH	
2016	Wilshire Detective Division, Volunteer	LAPD
2014	Venice Neighborhood Council, Member, Neighborhood Committee	CA
2009	Student Government, Treasurer	Naropa
DEVELOPME	ENT	
2020 - 2021	Data Scientist with Python, Certificate	DataCamp
Data Scientist with R, Certificate		
Data Visualization with R, Certificate		
Designing and Analyzing Clinical Trials in R, Certificate		
Machine Learning Scientist with Python, Certificate		
Machine Learning Scientist with R, Certificate		
Network Analysis with R, Certificate		
R Programmer, Certificate		
Shiny Fundamentals with R, Certificate Spatial Data with R, Certificate		
	Survival Analysis in R, Certificate	
	Statistician with R, Certificate	
	Time Series with R, Certificate	
		Six Sigma
2021	Certified Six Sigma Black Belt, Certificate	Academy
		Amsterdam